<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Browser Dashboard PWA Blog</title>
        <link>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog</link>
        <description>Browser Dashboard PWA Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rework for DDD]]></title>
            <link>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/rework-for-ddd</link>
            <guid>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/rework-for-ddd</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In the last several weeks I have been able to make good progress. I could use the generative AI to do the heavy work in]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the last several weeks I have been able to make good progress. I could use the generative AI to do the heavy work in
both the generation of the new DMD (Domain Modeling Document) and the refactor of the SRS (Software Requirement
Specification). In the process, I've consumed most of the AI credits (tokens) quota I have in the tool I'm using.</p>
<p>In next steps, I will also refactor the non-functional requirements and user stories when the quota gets renewed (which
will be next month).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="the-new-dmd">The new DMD<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/rework-for-ddd#the-new-dmd" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The new DMD" title="Direct link to The new DMD" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>Since two of my main purposes for this project was to both learn new skills and show proficiency in skills I already
have, I came to the conclusion that using DDD (Domain-Driven Development) could be a good addition. However, to do that,
I'd need to model the domain and business itself, prior to even think about creating a requirement specification.</p>
<p>In that regard, I've spent some time with the generative AI to create a common language (ubiquitous language) for all
stakeholders as well as defining the core domain and the subdomains.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="refactoring-the-srs">Refactoring the SRS<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/rework-for-ddd#refactoring-the-srs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Refactoring the SRS" title="Direct link to Refactoring the SRS" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>After modeling the domain, I had to completely refactor the SRS.</p>
<p>Since the business vision and the core business domain was clearly defined in the DMD, the business requirements in the
SRS could use a refactor to make them perfectly align with the domain model.</p>
<p>Also, since the boundaries of the different subdomains were now much more clearly defined, the functional requirements
were greatly refined, categorizing them by bounded context. Each bounded context has features, and each feature has
several scenarios. This was done to not only align with the DDD pattern but also with BDD (Behavior-Driven Development)
pattern, given we are going to use such a pattern while developing the system.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="other-tasks">Other tasks<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/rework-for-ddd#other-tasks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Other tasks" title="Direct link to Other tasks" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>I've also included a simple workflow that uses GitHub Actions to automatically deploy the documentation as GitHub Pages.</p>
<p>The idea is that whenever we push changes to the repository, the docusaurus project gets built and deployed into GitHub
pages. But we ensure to only do so when something changes inside the <code>/docs</code> folder. This way we avoid unnecessary runs.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Development</category>
            <category>Documentation</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Continuing the documentation]]></title>
            <link>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/continuing-the-documentation</link>
            <guid>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/continuing-the-documentation</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Throughout the last week, I could only work for short periods of time, due to my work. On those short spans, I have been]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Throughout the last week, I could only work for short periods of time, due to my work. On those short spans, I have been
refining the requirements. I also wanted to start the next phase — documenting the architecture — but I have not reached
that point yet, due to some issues with the generative AI tool I'm using.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="format-issues-with-the-generative-ai-tool">Format issues with the generative AI tool<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/continuing-the-documentation#format-issues-with-the-generative-ai-tool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Format issues with the generative AI tool" title="Direct link to Format issues with the generative AI tool" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>The tool I'm using to generate the documentation was good for the requirements. However, it was not good for the
architecture. To start with, since the LLMs usually generate their replies in Markdown format (or at least some variant
of it), and our <code>docusaurus</code> documentation is written in Markdown, the generated documentation had serious formatting
problems whenever the AI wanted to embed a code snippet inside the Markdown snippet itself. That caused the
documentation to be unreadable. The code snippet inside the Markdown snippet caused the latter to be broken and further
text was outside the Markdown snippet.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="content-issues-with-the-generative-ai-tool">Content issues with the generative AI tool<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/continuing-the-documentation#content-issues-with-the-generative-ai-tool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Content issues with the generative AI tool" title="Direct link to Content issues with the generative AI tool" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>With some workarounds, I was finally able to somehow get some parts of the documentation to be readable. However, I
found the next problem: the actual content of the documentation was not good enough for me.</p>
<p>I wanted to use some concepts like "C4 diagrams" (Context, Containers, Components, and Code) and the "4+1 Architectural
View Model" (Logical View, Physical View, Process View, Developer + View, and Scenario View). However, the LLM was not
able to understand the boundaries of these concepts and how to fit them into the documentation.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="other-issues">Other issues<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/continuing-the-documentation#other-issues" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Other issues" title="Direct link to Other issues" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>I also wanted to use some concepts like "Domain-Driven Design" and, after several attempts, I found it was better to use
another approach.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="the-solution-new-approach">The solution (new approach)<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/continuing-the-documentation#the-solution-new-approach" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The solution (new approach)" title="Direct link to The solution (new approach)" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>I tried a different LLM and asked for a different approach, considering my constraints and preferences. I was able to
get some good results. It opened up a new approach to the documentation: to fit the DDD concepts into the documentation,
it recommended adding a new section to the documentation, prior to the "Requirements" section.</p>
<p>This new section, Domain Model Document or DMD, will hold the business domain rules previous to the requirements. I will
most likely need to refactor the SRS part of the documentation to completely follow the new DMD. But in the long run,
I think it will be the best option.</p>
<p>I also asked the other LLM to suggest renamings to the sections of the documentation to be more consistent with industry
standards. I ended up renaming the following sections:</p>
<ol>
<li class="">the "SRD" (Software Requirements Document) to "SRS" (Software Specification Document), as it is the standard name
for the document.</li>
<li class="">the "ADD" (Architecture Design Document) to "SAD" (Software Architecture Document), as it is the standard name for
the document.</li>
<li class="">the "DDD" (Detailed Design Document) to "CDD" (Component Design Document). In this case, the first name was good and
standard, but it collided with the "DDD" acronym for Domain-Driven Design, which could be confusing for everyone. So
the AI suggested using the second name.</li>
</ol>
<p>Next, I asked the LLM about standards and best practices for documentation and how to write it. I ended up getting the
relevant ISO/IEC/IEEE standards as suggestions. However, due to the high cost of these standard files, I decided to not
make the documentation fully compliant with the latest versions of these standards. I could find previous versions of
some of these standards that, although withdrawn, are still relevant, I'm pretty sure.</p>
<p>Finally, the LLM also suggested a very high-level overview of each part of the documentation that I will follow from
now on. This includes where to fit the DDD concepts, the C4 diagrams, and the 4+1 Architectural View Model.</p>
<p>I will start each section of the documentation with that structure and then ask the LLM to fill in the details. After
that, I will review the documentation and make any necessary changes.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/continuing-the-documentation#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>Tomorrow Sunday, hopefully, I'll be able to finish the DMD and start the refactoring of the SRS following the new
approach.</p>
<p>I will then try some prompts to see if any of the LLMs can embed diagrams into the Markdown snippets without breaking
the formatting. I may even explain the problem to one LLM and ask it for a prompt for the other LLM. AI talking to each
other, what could possibly go wrong?</p>
<p>In all seriousness, I hope this new approach and the combination of more than one LLM will be a good solution in the
long term.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Development</category>
            <category>Documentation</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Documenting the requirements]]></title>
            <link>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/documenting-the-requirements</link>
            <guid>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/documenting-the-requirements</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Yesterday I started the project. Essentially, I created the repository locally and the]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I <a class="" href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/starting-the-project">started the project</a>. Essentially, I created the repository locally and the
bare bones of the project structure.</p>
<p>And today I started to document the requirements. How? With the help of generative AI.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="generative-ai-as-a-helper">Generative AI as a helper<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/documenting-the-requirements#generative-ai-as-a-helper" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Generative AI as a helper" title="Direct link to Generative AI as a helper" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>I started by creating an initial version of the whole SRS (Software Requirements Specification) with the help of
generative AI. With that I got a very basic structure of the document very quickly, that I then needed to review and
refine — adding, removing or editing some details — both manually and also with the help of generative AI.</p>
<p>The initial prompt was this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This project is intended to be a monorepo (storing backend, frontend, documentation and infrastructure modules) of a
fullstack project to enrich my portfolio as a developer.</p>
<p>The idea is to have a sort of dashboard PWA for the browser, pretty much like the one the vivaldi browser has. Modules
that I plan to create include:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">bookmarks (with links and folders of links, to showcase mostly frontend proficiency, like grids, animations, etc.)</li>
<li class="">task list (the typical simple and very visual project, to showcase a simple CRUD)</li>
<li class="">weather (to showcase the usage of third party/external APIs)</li>
<li class="">calendar (to showcase management of events and integration with the task list module)</li>
</ul>
<p>The documentation part is a docusaurus project (for now, just the "classic" preset with the defaults). And I plan to
have the full range of documentation: requirements → architecture → detailed designs.</p>
<p>Can you help me start with the requirements' documentation?</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="the-result">The result<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/documenting-the-requirements#the-result" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The result" title="Direct link to The result" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>The first reply was very positive, and I was able to create a great starting point for the requirements with the very
complete reply I got from the generative AI.</p>
<p>And the final result is satisfactory, a requirements document with a lot of details and information. I'm sure that it
will be invaluable for the future development of the project. Business, functional, non-functional and system
requirements are all covered, which will help me a lot in future iterations of the documentation and development
processes.</p>
<p>It can be found <a class="" href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/docs/requirements/overview">here</a>.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="other-tasks">Other tasks<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/documenting-the-requirements#other-tasks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Other tasks" title="Direct link to Other tasks" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>In other matters, I also created the repository remotely on my GitHub account as a public repository. The repository
will hold every single piece of the project, from documentation to source code and infrastructure.</p>
<p>And as another minor task, I also created (with the help of generative AI as well) a Nord theme for Docusaurus, covering
light and dark mode.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/documenting-the-requirements#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>In the next days, I will keep using the generative AI for the next document (SAD, Software Architecture Document) pretty
much as I did for the SRS. First generate, then review, finally refine (manually and with AI).</p>
<p>When the architecture is ready and the system is divided into modules, I will continue with the documentation of each
one of them.</p>
<p>Depending on how refined the detailed documentation is, I may very well start the development of some parts since the
contracts between the modules will be available. Just to mix some development and documentation. Time will tell.</p>
<p>In any case, I will try to keep posting here about the progress of the project, whether it's about the documentation or
the development.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Development</category>
            <category>Documentation</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starting the project]]></title>
            <link>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/starting-the-project</link>
            <guid>https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/starting-the-project</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On the 11th of October 2025, I'm starting the Browser Dashboard PWA Project. It's a full-stack project to add to my]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the 11th of October 2025, I'm starting the Browser Dashboard PWA Project. It's a full-stack project to add to my
portfolio.</p>
<p>It will consist of a set of different modules and widgets to help users in their daily browsing experience. It is going
to be open-source, available on GitHub.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="project-goals">Project goals<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/starting-the-project#project-goals" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Project goals" title="Direct link to Project goals" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>The main goal of the project is to showcase my skills and experience as a full-stack developer and engineer in several
areas.</p>
<ul>
<li class="">The <code>docs</code> (documentation) part will show my skills in the analysis, architecture and design areas.</li>
<li class="">The <code>infra</code> part will show my skills in the <em>devops</em>, CI/CD and infrastructure areas.</li>
<li class="">The <code>source</code> part (both backend and frontend) will show my skills in the development area, specially, the development
of REST APIs (backend) and PWAs (frontend).</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="project-modules-and-widgets">Project modules and widgets<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/starting-the-project#project-modules-and-widgets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Project modules and widgets" title="Direct link to Project modules and widgets" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>The different modules I have planned for now are:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Bookmark manager (to save frequently visited sites in a nested way, with 'folders' and 'links')</li>
<li class="">Task list manager (to save tasks and their status)</li>
<li class="">Calendar (to save events, integrated with the task list manager)</li>
<li class="">Weather (to show the weather in a specific location, from third-party APIs)</li>
</ul>
<p>The user must be able to configure the widgets and save their preferences. And, since it's a PWA, it must be able to
work offline (at least certain parts of the app).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="first-steps">First steps<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/starting-the-project#first-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First steps" title="Direct link to First steps" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>I created the repository locally with the main structure consisting of <code>docs</code> (a docusaurus project, what you're seeing
now, actually), <code>infra</code> (what will be an IaC and devops project) and <code>source</code> (which will be divided into two parts:
<code>backend</code> and <code>frontend</code>, with the actual source code of the project).</p>
<p>I also created a <code>mise.toml</code> file (<a href="https://mise.jdx.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">mise-en-place</a>) to manage tool versions and also some tasks.
In the past, I used Makefiles. However, since I started using mise as a tool version manager — and since I found it had
a lot more than just 'version management' — I decided to give it a try for task management as well.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_eVCZ" id="next-steps">Next steps<a href="https://migmolrod.github.io/browser-dashboard-pwa/blog/starting-the-project#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next steps" title="Direct link to Next steps" translate="no">​</a></h3>
<p>This is just the beginning of the project. I will start with the documentation part (requirements, architecture, general
design and detailed design), using this blog as a way to document my progress.</p>
<p>Since it's just a personal project, I will be able to spend only a little time on it. It probably will not be deployed
in a production environment for long, but it will have a well-documented README to help start and try the project in
your own local environment, anyway.</p>
<p>And, what is more important, it will have an easy way to quickly deploy it in a production environment in case it's
necessary, thanks to an IaC and DevOps approach. Or, if we find good enough solutions with a free tier, we can maybe
deploy it indefinitely to avoid the hassle of having to deploy it each time I need to show it to recruiters, clients,
employers, etc.</p>
<p>Let's see how it goes!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Development</category>
            <category>Documentation</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>